All right, let's do it.
>> I feel like every time you take those
pictures and like someone shows them,
they're like, "Give us give a f You're
like you purposely pause it on the on
the bad part."
>> Nick and I have this this theory that is
this going to be like in the transcript
when we write this? It's going to
>> off the record.
>> We have this theory that like anytime
you guys try to take a picture of us,
it's like, "Let me find let me look at
five pictures. Let me find them in the
most awkward place and then put it down
there." It'll be like this. He'll be
like, "Oh,
>> now he took that picture."
>> Okay. All right. We're a little slap
happy. It's been a while. What do we
got?
>> When you traded down, uh, you got the
extra picks. Was that with UAR in mind?
Did you want to secure that player?
>> Yeah, we did. Um, you know, it was
funny. It was um
when we were doing the trade with
Minnesota yesterday, adding in that
seventh this year was important. Um we
try to get in a couple trades that we
were discussing. Uh we want we wanted to
take the chance on the kid. Um obviously
um we've had great success with that
program. Um we spent a lot of time with
him. Um Coach Her went down there and
spent the day with him, worked him out.
Um you know, just for us it it was a
passion project. you know, obviously got
a lot of tools in his body. Understand
it's going to take time. You know, it's
going to take a lot of time here, but um
you know, it's pretty cool. Pretty cool.
And um it's just, you know, we spent a
lot of time talking about unusual, you
know, and and certainly unusual uh with
that guy. So,
>> when's the first time you when's the
first time you heard his name and what
was the process like trying to figure
out who he was and what he could do?
>> Um I I think we we found out his name.
our scouts. We we we um we focus on the
IP after the combine a little bit in
that spot and um we have a dedicated
scout to that.
>> Um and they gave us the heads up on him
and then we watched the workout and uh
you saw the testing numbers. Um and then
coach her went down there, worked him
out. Um the workouts continued to come
in. You know, we continued to see him
work out more and more. Um and um you
know I think what what's cool is um
we're also going to sign we were from
that program from that IP program. So
we're going to bring both of them here.
Um which is really cool you know for
them to be together. Um they worked out
together. They were doing all their
training together and he's another guy
who's got unique traits in his body. And
so um we signed both those guys.
>> How how uh satisfied are you with with
your safety after this draft?
Um, you know, I think again, you go into
this understanding that you're going to
come out of it with not everything
perfect, but um, probably have a
different vision of our safety room than
maybe uh, you know, it is publicly, but
again, you know, that'll all sort itself
out. We don't play our first game till
September um, at every position. You
know, we got to see what we have and if
we went into the draft and we filled
every hole, we probably wouldn't have
had a good draft, you know, and it's yet
to remains to be seen if we even had a
good draft. You know, we'll see here. we
got time to judge it, but um understood
that we couldn't get everything we
wanted uh at any position. Um very
comfortable where we are as a football
team right now and understanding that
there's more work to be done.
>> If I could ask both of you guys about
all the additions, offensive skill guys,
the three receivers you signed or
acquired, the one you drafted and the
tight end you drafted, you've added a
lot of skill guys to that to that
offense and kind of what you've added
just what do you feel like you've added
with those guys?
Yeah, we'll see. You know, obviously we
got to get these guys uh on the grass
and and see how it all comes together.
Um, everyone we signed, you know, I tell
our players all the time, there's no
allocation draft in the National
Football League. You know, everyone that
is on this team, we've chosen. We've
chosen because, uh, we have a level of
like of their skill set of the person.
And so, uh, from that perspective, you
know, we brought all those guys in
because we thought that they they can do
some things for our team. But um you
know we haven't we haven't had one one
practice on the field yet and so um yet
to be seen how it all comes together.
>> The the gap between 68 and 178 was um at
the very least longest since at least
you first named Jim. I'm just curious
what that time period was like for you
and how you treated
>> I don't know how I treat it.
>> Good energy
>> always. Good uh yeah good talk back and
forth everything. Yeah, it was long. You
know, I think it was daunting when, you
know, um John Ferrari's in in the back
of the room always and he'd be like, "We
get the ninth player." And, you know,
after we picked at 68, he goes, "Um, we
get the 110th next player." And it's
like, "Oh my gosh, that's going to be a
long time." Um, you know, and I think
for us it it was just understanding that
there were good players on the board.
And I think this is how we started the
day because we start today with a
passion meeting from our scouts. Um, and
there's a lot of guys on that. You know,
there's a lot of guys that we want to
draft on day three and always looking
for more picks. But I think when we look
at it from a big picture perspective,
you know, something that that I said
was, yeah, it it hurt for those hours. I
don't know what those hours were, you
know, last night when we picked whatever
time that was to when we picked today.
Um, it didn't feel great. But the most
important thing is how we feel each
weekend coming home from those games.
And so some of the things that we did
and giving up those picks, they were to
make us the best possible team during
the season. And so um obviously you're
giving up some players there. You're
giving up players. You're at those
picks. You're going, "This is who I pick
at that guy. He's pretty good. I like
that. I'd be excited about that." But we
can't lose sight of the guys that we
brought in with those picks. And we
expect those guys um that we traded up
for um that we traded for to make a big
difference on our football team. And
that's what we're looking for. We're
looking for difference makers and we
feel like we we got the opportunity to
get them. They cost, you know, um for
sure it wasn't cheap to get them, but we
believe it'll be worth it.
>> Why was I'm sorry.
>> As a followup to that, when you make the
trade on Thursday, you don't know who's
going to be there in the fourth round.
You don't know even who 23 would be.
>> Seeing how it all played out, does it
affect the way you view the trade? Does
it fortify the way you view the trade?
>> Yeah, I don't I don't really um play a
lot of whatifs. Um, you know, my mind
doesn't really work like that. Um, I
would just say feel really good about
the decision we made to trade up for
Mai. Um, feel really good about the
decision we made to bring in um, JG
here, John here to Philly. Um, obviously
it's got to play out. You know, I
understand that. Uh, there's no
guarantee about anything, but definitely
uh, no regrets. And again, that being
said, we t we have those picks. Would
have been really excited about those
picks. you know, the players that we
would have picking taken at those picks
would have been excited to have those
guys and talk about them, but just feel
like the impact that we could get from
the decisions we made um could really
push us forward in a positive way.
>> Why was Cole Payton um someone you
targeted in the fifth round? What do you
like about what he brings to the table?
>> Yeah, really, really athletic um uh
really good with the ball in his hands,
you know, in the quarterback run game.
um made were great decisions with the
football, accurate passer, as you know,
72% um last year as a starter. Um and
and you can't be that unless you're
making good accurate throws and and uh
and going the right place with the ball.
Um but there's some wow plays on his
tape uh that are really impressive. I I
mean, I think I charted like four times
he jumped over somebody and or wrote
down a bunch of times he's the best
athlete on the field. big, strong, um,
you know, excited, really excited about
him.
>> Are you open to Are you open to finding
a way to get him on the field?
>> Yeah, we'll see. Yeah, we'll see. Um,
we'll see how that goes. Um, we're going
to get him here, get him acclimated
here, and, uh, be have a chance for that
next weekend at at rookie mini camp. Um,
learning the playbook and then we'll see
where we go from there.
>> Why a quarterback? You you already have
a pretty crowded quarterback room, so
what what went into that decision?
>> Yeah, really. uh as we got into the
fifth round, late in the fifth round,
almost the sixth round, um you know, the
the board kind of played itself out that
way and um he was the highest guy on the
board and obviously it's an important
position. Um you know, we feel really
good about the three quarterbacks that
are here. You know, um we plan to have
them here. Uh we're excited to have the
all those three guys here. This has
nothing to do with them. Uh it was about
staying true to the process that we were
going into and um taking the best player
available obviously at an important
position and um you know we'll let it
play out. You know we've talked about it
or we're open to carrying four
quarterbacks for sure. You know when you
talk about if you talk about it being
the most important position in sports
and you have four good ones why wouldn't
you keep them? Uh it's no different than
when we keep 11 offensive linemen
because we think we have a good
offensive lineman or extra defensive
lineman. So, you know, for us, um, if we
weren't going to take him just because
of what we had at a position right now,
it didn't really seem to make sense. It
wasn't really consistent with our
philosophy. And so, we took the player.
>> Position coach who are you won't be who
are position coach obviously, but what's
sort of your experience coaching guys
who don't have football playing
experience at this position coach? I
mean,
>> yeah, you know, what do you what do you
envision that kind of looking like? just
that, you know, I think that uh we had
this experience with um obviously they
the Eagles have had it with Jordan. Uh I
was able to be around Moi Cox who was
coming from basketball. Um just kind of
a blank slate that you're able to to
teach things to and look really look
forward to that, right? To teaching them
the game, to teaching them the
fundamentals of the game, uh to teaching
them the situations that we go through,
right? Shoot. I mean, and the
fundamentals even are even more basic
than uh to start things off. And so,
just that, you know, that whole process
of of learning the game, learning what
it takes to be on a on a football team,
all the different things that come with
it. So, it's an exciting uh an exciting
thing to be a part of, and you know, uh
I know with the guys in this locker room
and the people that we have here that
he's going to have a great experience as
far as his football experience. So, um,
let's just looking to develop him and
and continue to get him better.
>> I enjoyed doing like a performance. What
do you like about him?
>> Yeah, there's a lot to like about him.
Um, I mean, he's got great size. Um, you
know, all his testing is through the
roof. Um, you know, he's a started every
game for Georgia this year. He's got
incredible experience playing in the
SEC. You know, he's got all the ability
and now he's got to apply that, you
know, as he gets an opportunity to come
here. So, um, another guy just, uh, as
we were going through it, um, stood out
on our board for where we were and
obviously in an important position and
so, um, we took them.
>> I know the roster acquisition is not
finished yet, but
>> if you look at at these past few months,
what do you think you've accomplished
and how do you think you you've done
this offseason?
>> Yeah, I I I think that I probably need
to get some perspective on Zach on that
question, Zach, to answer that question
accurately. You know, this weekend goes
fast. Um, and I think that if we're
really staying true to the process,
we're not getting into what what are we
looking for, what do we need, and we're
just staying true to the process of the
draft. And so, uh, I'll take some time
to reflect on that and put together a
plan of how to address other things. And
again, you know, um, our work isn't
done. We're not going on vacation, uh,
here. Um, you know, we're going to do
whatever we can to put the best possible
team forward in September. Um, and then
obviously, so it's playing deep into
January and hopefully February. I was
just sure you're not drafting players
for schemes, but the first two picks,
Mai and Eli, as you're like envisioning
them and what they're going to look
like, how much was Sean's offense a part
of that vision?
>> Yeah, you know, you talk about um you're
not drafting guys for scheme, but you're
really drafting guys um based on a bunch
of factors. You're drafting because you
like the tape. You're drafting because
the numbers match up. You're drafting
because it's a scheme fit. You're
drafting because they have good
character. um you're drafting um also
because you know the vision of the
player fits uh of what we're doing and
you're drafting because they have good
medical, right? And so you're putting
all those factors together and you're
trying to come up with a draft board.
And so um you know certainly like I
could like a player but if we have a a
conversation with the coaches and
there's no vision for that player, it's
not going to work out very well. So
everything we do is alignment. Um and
making sure we're making good decisions
that make sense that can get the best
out of the player because you know I'm
not going to look good. Nick's not going
to look good if there's no alignment.
>> Nick, how's the installation of a new
offense going at this at this stage
versus other times that you've had new
offensive coordinators and scheme
changes?
>> Yeah, I think Sean's doing a great job.
We've only had the players in here for a
week. Um it's a good start to meetings.
Um, and so I think we're on we're in a
good good spot, good progress, and uh,
yeah, I like where we are right now.
>> We spoke to Mai yesterday. He talked a
little bit about his first year at USC.
He wasn't getting on the field as a
receiver, played a little bit of
cornerback, but ultimately decided to to
stay there. When you are, you know,
looking at that year in the context of
his career there, um, I guess what did
you learn from from that and what you
uncovered, not necessarily about his
onfield performance, but like who he is
as a person?
one, he's got tremendous confidence in
his own abilities. You know, I think
that, you know, that and that um
adversity wasn't going to deter him from
um going forward in in achieving his
goals. You know, he wanted to do it
there. Um he's a very determined guy.
He's got great work ethic. Um he loves
football and I think all those things
play out when you see stories like that.
>> Don't want him to get lost in the
shuffle. Keshan, I think uh just what
did you like about him uh late in the
draft?
>> He can rush. Uh I think that when you
turn on the tape and you see him in must
pass situations, he able to get off the
ball, he can bend. Um he's got
production as a rusher. Um and so
obviously you're looking for traits late
in the draft. And um that was one of the
reasons we wanted to get a bunch of
picks there at the end because we had a
bunch of guys that we wanted to take. I
mean, even at the end, we were sitting
there going, you know, can we try to get
a couple more picks because there were
some guys that we wanted to get. So, um,
again, he's going to have to show it
here. But, um, that's why we liked him.
>> When you when you look at when you look
at guys that you've hit with in late
rounds like Jordan, Morrow, Joo, and
everything,
>> you know, when you're when you're like
looking at who to pick in those late
rounds, is there a common theme and
stuff? Is it just thinking outside the
box?
There's really there's really two two
kinds of players that hit late when we
study it, you know, there's guys that
that have unique traits, you know, and I
think when you talk about Jordan and
Morrow, those are those guys. And then
there are just guys that, you know, are
just really good players, you know, and
you see that through production, you see
that through instincts. Um, everything
in life revolves around instincts. no
matter what you're doing, no matter what
field you're in. That's speaking from
someone who's never done anything else
other than this in his life, but um and
so I think that, you know, you see that
you see that in a player like Reed, you
know, you see that in a seventh round
pick like Jaylen Mills, you know, and
those guys, they just have a great
football sense, football IQ. Um and so I
think, you know, that if you look at our
picks in the seventh, you'll see some
unique traits, right? obviously who are
and then you'll see just really good
players like Cole, you know, and so um
th that's really the the two groups of
players we're looking for in
>> Do you enjoy the seventh question?
>> Um really instinctive. Uh he's got great
ball skills. Um he's a physical player.
Uh really really good physical player
and you know obviously there's some
reminder of a guy we won a Super Bowl
with. Obviously, that's a that's a those
are tough shoes to fill, but when you
watched him, you saw some of the things
you you liked on on Reed. Um I mean,
that would be an unbelievable outcome,
you know, unbelievable career that Reed
had. You know, miss that guy for sure.
Um but that that's that's some of the
things that we saw. Howie, do you miss
do you enjoy the seventh round more than
the other rounds just because it's such
a
>> I mean the hit rate is so low so it kind
of you know you really get to it just
seems like you
>> No, I like when there's great players
and we get a chance to pick them first,
you know. I think that that's my most
fun. The seventh round you're you got a
mixture of chaos after the draft and
then on the clock. Um, and it and it's
it's obviously, you know, it's a
different point in the draft, you know,
so um, no, I I I like every part of
about the draft though.
>> Your background is in offense,
obviously, but it's been a long time
since you've had like this volume of
young offensive players, um, up to the
draft. How do you approach getting these
guys ready to play because you haven't
had to play young guys on offense in a
while?
>> Yeah. Um, similar. you know, you're
still going to we're still going to be
obsessive about the detail of the
fundamentals, the situational football,
the things that require the mastering
the things that require no talent. Um,
you know, those are those are the big
parts of the in of the detail portion of
it. Uh, and then the the toughness
portion of it, just teaching them what
what was required from us as far as
mental toughness, um, the effort,
relentless effort, um, you know, the
physical toughness, and then just
teaching these guys how to play
together. So, it's it's still going to
go back, you know, I don't care if I'm
coaching high school, college, pro,
young guys that are in it, old guys that
have been in it, but it's going to still
be down to those basic things. um the
toughness, the detail together. So,
we'll we'll start I'll show them exactly
um you know and tell them exactly what
is required from me. I'll show them what
it looks like and I'll be relentless in
in uh in the approach of keeping that
standard. How do you think Lemon and
>> Adamry?
>> How do you think Lemon and Sters, two
two guys who worked a lot of the middle
field as a slot and the tight end are
going to help the offense as Mark works
with you under center play action?
>> Areas where you guys kind of didn't do
that as much previous?
>> Yeah, I think that that you know
obviously both these guys are extremely
quick in and out of the break. um you
know with and then you know Eli is very
um unusual as far as his his size and
his his catch radius. Um Mai you know
being able to separate at the top of the
route and the things that he can do
after the catch. Um and there's
different ways uh to be able to get them
the football in the drop back game and
the play action game. Um we want to be
able to exploit every part of the field
deep, intermediate, in the middle,
outside the numbers. Um and these guys
will help us do that. When it comes to
the the players in in day three who have
the trades, obviously the next part of
that is the developmental program, how
much has that changed and been altered
throughout the course of your time here.
How?
>> Yeah, we're constantly evolving the
things that we do. You know, we're
looking at it. U for me, this is a good
time of year to do that in May and June
to uh kind of understand where we've
been and where we're trying to go. Uh
what other people are doing in our sport
and in different sports. Um, and it's
it's really an opportunity for us um to
continue to grow in that area. It's it's
really um there's a lot of room for us
to grow in it, and I think we have the
right people to do that.
>> All right. Thanks, folks.